Guide to the John Seelye Papers, 1862-2015 and undated RL.11381
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
John Seelye Papers
1862-2015 and undated
1955-2007
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Seelye, John, 1931-2015
RL.11381
46.7 Linear Feet
0.065 Gigabytes
John Seelye was a professor of English and American Literature at the University of California at Berkeley, University of Connecticut, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Dartmouth College, and the University of Florida. The papers of John Seelye span the years 1862-2015, with the bulk of the papers dated between 1955 and 2007, covering Seelye's professional career as both an scholar and as an editor of the Penguin Classics series for literature. Although there are files related to his teaching and career as an academic, the emphasis of the collection is on Seelye's work as author and editor. The collection consists of correspondence (sent and received) and contracts; subject files Seelye maintained at each of his institutions and for his research; writings by Seelye, including book reviews, poetry, articles and prose, as well as books, including a copy of the Life of Asa G. Sheldon: Wilmington Farmer (1862); and personal items, which include incoming correspondence intended for Suzanne Everett Throop, who received a large number of love letters from "Marguerite" between 1897 and 1898 and some additional letters from "Harriet" and "Chandler" in the 1920s. Subjects in the papers include Mark Twain, the literary criticism and interpretation of Herman Melville's works and American literature generally, the West in fiction, rivers in the United States, cowboys in popular culture, the history of Plymouth Rock, and the publishing of poetry in the United States.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Correspondence, Academia, Research/Subject files, Writings, and Personal.
Biographical / Historical
John Seelye was a professor of English and American Literature at the University of California at Berkeley, University of Connecticut, University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Dartmouth College, and the University of Florida. He received his M.A. and Ph.D. from Claremont Graduate School. A writer, reviewer, and scholar who wrote on a variety of subjects, in 1979 Seelye became the general editor of the Penguin Classics of American Literature. He also edited works of American literature for Oxford University Press and for the Everyman Library.
Access Restrictions
Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Contact Research Services in advance to request the production of listening copies.
Provenance
The John Seelye Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2017 and 2019.
Collection Overview
The papers of John Seelye span the years 1862-2015, with the bulk of the papers dated between 1955 and 2007, covering Seelye's professional career as both an scholar and as an editor of the Penguin Classics series for literature. Although there are files related to his teaching and career as an academic, the emphasis of the collection is on Seelye's work as author and editor. The Correspondence and Contracts Series includes primarily professional correspondence sent (1956-2014) and received (1958-2012 and undated) by Seelye, as well as contracts and supporting documents focusing on Seelye's contact with his publishers. The Academia Series contains subject files Seelye maintained during his professional career while at the University of California at Berkeley (1959-1965), the University of Connecticut (1966-1974), the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (1974-1984), the University of Florida (1984-2008), and Dartmouth (1982-1992). The Research/Subject Files Series includes materials related to research Seelye carried out to support his writings as well as subject files on people and topics of interest to him or related to other work he carried out. The Writings Series contains drafts, notes, edits, and published versions of Seelye's book reviews, film reviews, poetry, and prose, including his numerous scholarly and fiction essays and articles, books, and edited works. The Personal series contains assorted materials relevant to Seelye's life, including several versions of his curriculum vitae as well as early report cards, photographs and headshots, and school newspapers from his various schools. Also includes a Bible owned by Dwight L. Moody and incoming correspondence intended for Suzanne Everett Throop, including a large number of love letters from "Marguerite" between 1897 and 1898 and some additional letters from "Harriet" and "Chandler" in the 1920s. Subjects in the papers include Mark Twain, the literary criticism and interpretation of Herman Melville's works and American literature generally, the West in fiction, rivers in the United States, cowboys in popular culture, the history of Plymouth Rock, and the publishing of poetry in the United States.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection contains electronic records that must be requested and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
Conditions Governing Access
Access restricted. In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records. Contact Research Services for more information.
American literature -- History and criticism; Authors, American -- 20th century; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Correspondence; Cowboys in popular culture; Editors -- United States; Female friendship -- United States -- History -- 19th century; Female friendship -- United States -- History -- 20th century; Love-letters -- United States -- History -- 19th century; Lesbians -- United States -- History -- 19th century; Penguin classics; Plymouth Rock (Plymouth, Mass.) -- History; Poetry -- Publishing -- United States; Rivers -- United States; West (U.S.) -- Fiction; Seelye, John, 1931-2015; University of California, Berkeley -- Faculty.; University of Connecticut -- Faculty; Dartmouth College -- Faculty.; University of Florida -- Faculty; University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill -- Faculty; Melville, Herman, 1819-1891 -- Criticism and interpretation; Twain, Mark, 1835-1910; Throop, Suzanne Everett
- Correspondence and Contracts, 1955-2014; undated; 1
  Scope and Contents
  The Correspondence and Contracts Series includes primarily professional correspondence sent (1956-2011) and received (1958-2012 and undated) by Seelye. There are letters from fellow academics and publishers as well as notices from institutions. Occasionally features items of a personal nature, especially following Seelye's retirement around 2008. The sent and received correspondence is arranged chronologically, and includes a few subject files Seelye maintained for individuals. The series also features contracts and supporting documents focusing on Seelye's contact with his publishers. Includes contracts; general publishing correspondence sent and received, some concentrating on publishing rights and permissions; a few illustrations; along with reviews and reader's reports, when available, for his works. The contracts and supporting documents are arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Original audiovisual materials are closed to use. Contact Research Services in advance to request the production of listening copies.
  Collection contains electronic records that must be requested and accessed in our reading room. Contact Research Services with questions.
  Access restricted. In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records. Contact Research Services for more information.
  - Sent, 1956-2014; 1
    The Sent Correspondence Subseries includes professional correspondence sent (1956-2011) by Seelye. The material is arranged chronologically.
    - Literary and scholarly received and sent, 1956-1962 (Box 1)
    - Scholarly literature, 1962-1963 (Box 1)
    - Sent correspondence, 1963-1964; 4 folders (Box 1)
    - Berkeley, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
    - Sent correspondence, 1965-1981; 23 folders (Box 1)
    - Sent correspondence, 1982-2011; 14 folders (Box 2)
    - Sent correspondence, 2002-2014 (Box 28)
  - Received, 1958-2012; undated; 2
    The Received Correspondence Subseries includes primarily professional correspondence received (1958-2012 and undated) by Seelye. There are letters from fellow academics and publishers as well as notices from institutions. Occasionally features items of a personal nature, especially following Seelye's retirement around 2008. The correspondence is arranged chronologically, and includes a few subject files Seelye maintained for individuals.
    - Received correspondence, 1958-1965; 4 folders (Box 2)
    - Belknap, John Harvard, 1964 (Box 2)
    - Received correspondence, 1962-1965 (Box 2)
    - Received correspondence, 1966-1971; 9 folders (Box 2)
    - Received correspondence, 1967-2011 (Box 28)
    - Hughes, Robert, 1971 (Box 2)
    - Received correspondence, 1972-1974; 7 folders (Box 2)
    - Received correspondence, 1975-1977; 9 folders (Box 3)
    - CPTV (Connecticut Public Television) Correspondence, 1977 (Box 3)
    - Received correspondence, 1978; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - Misc. projects and proposals, 1978 (Box 3)
    - Received correspondence, 1979-1987; 14 folders (Box 3)
    - Received correspondence, 1988-2012; undated; 9 folders (Box 4)
    - Buchanan, Cynthia, 2008 (Box 28)
  - Contracts and supporting documents, 1955-2009; undated; 3
    The Contracts and Supporting Documents Subseries focuses on Seelye's contact with his publishers. Includes contracts; general publishing correspondence sent and received, some concentrating on publishing rights and permissions; a few illustrations; along with reviews and reader's reports, when available, for his works. The contracts and supporting documents are arranged alphabetically.
    - American Art, 2005 (Box 4)
    - ANS (American Antiquarian Society) corres. (Artworks, etc.), 1990-1991 (Box 4)
    - Associated Univ. Presses, 2005-2007 (Box 4)
    - Bancroft corres., 1976-1977 (Box 4)
    - Bear illustrations, 1964 (Box 4)
    - Beautiful Machine, 1986-1990 (Box 4)
    - Beautiful Machine contract, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Beautiful Machine corres., 1990-1992; undated; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Beautiful Machine reviews, 1993 (Box 4)
    - Beautiful Machine lecture, National Humanities Center "Soundings", 1985; 2 cassettes (Box 26, Audio-cassette RL-11381-CS-001, RL-11381-CS-002)
      2 cassette tapes from a National Humanities Center program featuring Seelye discussing Beautiful Machine.
    - Burn, Barbara, 1972-1973 (Box 4)
    - Cambridge U Press Contract, corres., 1988-1990; undated (Box 4)
    - Columbia contracts, 1997-1998 (Box 4)
    - Columbia Companion to the 20th c. American Short Story, 1998 (Box 4)
    - Columbia Literary History of the United States, 1989; undated (Box 4)
    - Contracts (Books), 1962-1968 (Box 4)
    - Crockett at 200, 1987-1988 (Box 4)
    - Crockett pictures, undated (Box 4)
    - Davis and Theodore Roosevelt photographs (Culver), undated (Box 4)
    - Dirty Tricks rights revision, 1988 (Box 4)
    - Elmo, 1994-2000 (Box 4)
    - Etchings reviews etc., 1968-1969 (Box 4)
    - Finding Colonial Americas, 2000-2001 (Box 4)
    - First Encounter Anthology Prospectus, undated (Box 4)
    - First Encounter Reader's reports/ corres., 1974; undated (Box 4)
    - Frederick Remington photographs, 1987 (Box 4)
    - Frederick Remington photographs for Rodriguez, undated (Box 4)
    - Garland Publishing, 1991 (Box 4)
    - Harper's, 1972; 1997 (Box 4)
    - Huck corres., 1985-1987; 2006 (Box 4)
    - Huckleberry Finn reviews, 1970-1971; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Jane Eyre's American Daughters, 2005 (Box 4)
    - John Steinbeck essay, 2003 (Box 4)
    - The Kid: Nebraska contract, 1981-1982 (Box 4)
    - The Kid copyright, 1972 (Box 4)
    - The Kid corres., 1981-1982 (Box 4)
    - The Kid reviews advance, 1971-1972 (Box 4)
    - The Kid reviews, 1972; undated (Box 4)
    - The Kid reviews (duplicates), 1972; undated (Box 4)
    - The Kid movie rights, 1972 (Box 4)
    - The Kid film rights, 1972-1977 (Box 4)
    - The Kid royalties, 1983 (Box 4)
    - The Kid: Ann Elmo, 1986 (Box 4)
    - The Kid: Elmo, 1980-1993; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - The Kid: Gene Jackson, 1984-1986 (Box 4)
    - The Kid: Margolin cont., 1980 (Box 4)
    - The Kid: Monte Diamond, 1987 (Box 4)
    - The Kid: Ramey Ward, 1989-1991 (Box 4)
    - The Kid movie: Zilber, 1978-1980 (Box 4)
    - Lew Carlson, 1992-1993; undated (Box 4)
    - Literary contracts, 1986-1987 (Box 4)
    - Liveright Publicity file, 1973; undated (Box 4)
    - Lois Poems, 1983; undated (Box 4)
    - Lyons Journals corres., 1984-1986; 2 folders (Box 4)
    - Lyons Journals--Bancroft, 1982-1985 (Box 4)
    - Lyons Journals--Gribben et al., 1982-1987 (Box 4)
    - Lyons Journals--McClury, 1982 (Box 4)
    - Lyons Journals--Moore, 1982-1985 (Box 4)
    - Lyons Journals--Strong, 1982-1985; undated (Box 4)
    - Lyons Journals--Vassar, 1981-1985 (Box 4)
    - Mark Twain in the Movies contract, 1976 (Box 4)
    - MTiTM (Mark Twain in the Movies) copyright, 1977 (Box 4)
    - MTiTM (Mark Twain in the Movies) correspondence, 1976-1977; undated (Box 4)
    - MTiTM (Mark Twain in the Movies) reviews, 1977-1978 (Box 4)
    - Mark Twain (Oxford), 1989-1992 (Box 4)
    - Mark Twain pictures, etc., correspondence Nat'l Portrait gallery, MT Memorial, 1989-1992 (Box 4)
    - Memory's Nation reader's reports, 1996-1997; undated (Box 5)
    - Memory's Nation reviews, 1998-2000; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Millsman paper illustrations, undated (Box 5)
    - MLA corres., 1992 (Box 5)
    - New Republic/Peretz, 1971-1984 (Box 5)
    - New York Magazine, 1971 (Box 5)
    - Nick Noxin contract, 1973 (Box 5)
    - Nick Noxin: pre-pub correspondence, reader's reports, 1973-1974; undated (Box 5)
    - Noah Dietrich contract (void), 1976 (Box 5)
    - U of Oklahoma Press (Old West, etc.), 1999-2000; undated (Box 5)
    - Oxford: Sisler, 1986-1988 (Box 5)
    - Padre Press--L. MacDonald, 1983 (Box 5)
    - Penguin, 2006 (Box 5)
    - Penguin Classics editorship, 2000 (Box 5)
    - Penguin: Tarzan contract, 1989 (Box 5)
    - Penguin: Thoreau contract, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Permissions, General, 1992-1993 (Box 5)
    - Pierre, Kavanaugh contract, 1996 (Box 5)
    - Plains of Kansas contract, 1972 (Box 5)
    - Poe--Everyman, 1991-1992; undated (Box 5)
    - Ponicsan/ Elmo, 2003-2009 (Box 5)
    - Prophetic Waters: Publicity, 1975-1977; undated (Box 5)
    - Prophetic Waters: Reversion of rights, 1994 (Box 5)
    - Prophectic Waters: Reviews, 1977-1980; 2 folders (Box 5)
    - Reprint Permissions, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Richard Harding Davis and the Origins of the Spanish-American War photograph, 2001 (Box 5)
    - RHD (Richard Harding Davis) book--corres., 1999-2004 (Box 5)
    - RHD (Richard Harding Davis) book-- reader's reports, 1999; undated (Box 5)
    - RHD (Richard Harding Davis) book-- reviews, 2004-2006 (Box 5)
    - River Book-- Corres. Gen'l, 1976; undated (Box 5)
    - River Book--Oxford Corres., 1975-1977 (Box 5)
    - River Book: Oxford and miscell. corres., 1973-1975 (Box 5)
    - River Books: Prophetic Waters and Beautiful Machine, 1974 (Box 5)
    - River Series Twin Cities TV, undated (Box 5)
    - Robert Bolling woos Anne Miller, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Russell and Volkening --Agents (Seldes and Muccovy), 1982-1984 (Box 5)
    - Sewanee Review, 1982 (Box 5)
    - Shapiro Remington, 1986 (Box 5)
    - Signet contracts, 1999 (Box 5)
    - Signet--C[Hrum?], 1999-2000 (Box 5)
    - Slotta (Mark Twain) corres., 1989-1993 (Box 5)
    - Smithsonian, 2005 (Box 5)
    - Stories of the Old West, 2001; undated (Box 5)
    - Stories of the Old West: corres. and contents, 1993 (Box 5)
    - Tom Sawyer 1st, 1955-1981; undated (Box 5)
    - Univ. of Fla.--contract, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
    - U Mass corres., 2000-2001; undated (Box 5)
    - UNC Press, 1995-1998 (Box 5)
    - U Press of NE: Contract, 1987-1988 (Box 5)
    - U Press of NE: Yankee Drover, 1988; 1990 (Box 5)
    - Valley News, 1992 (Box 5)
    - Virginian: Penguin, 1984-1985 (Box 5)
    - Vicking/Penguin Water Anthology contract, 1990 (Box 5)
    - Wing correspondence, 1961-1968 (Box 5)
- Academia, 1958-2009; undated; 2
  The Academia Series contains subject files Seelye maintained during his professional career while at the University of California at Berkeley (1959-1965), the University of Connecticut (1966-1974), the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill (1974-1984), the University of Florida (1984-2008), and Dartmouth (1982-1992). A few files date from the period following Seelye's retirement in 2008. Beyond files for each institution, the series includes Seelye's first published paper (1958); teaching files, especially multiple files for a seminar on the 1930s he taught at the University of Connecticut in 1969; files for organizations with which Seelye was involved, such as Mystic Seaport, Popular Culture Association, and Phi Beta Kappa; and files for Hubble Award decisions. There are also files related to his teaching periods at Dartmouth College, his personal job searches, the American Literature Section of the Modern Language Association; and his work associated with grants from the National Endowment for the Humanities.
  - General files, 1958-1969; 24 folders (Box 5)
  - General files, 1969-2003; 105 folders (Box 6)
  - General files, 2004-2009; undated; 14 folders (Box 7)
  - Conferences, etc., 1966-2004; 25 folders (Box 7)
  - Dartmouth, 1982-1992; undated; 13 folders (Box 7)
  - Fliers for readings, 1974-2002 and undated (Box 28)
  - Job searches, 1964-1989; 20 folders (Box 7)
  - MLA American Lit. Section, 1979-1988; 8 folders (Box 7)
  - NEH, 1979-1995; 14 folders (Box 8)
  - Steinbeck Conference, Hofstra University, March 2002 (Box 28)
- Research/Subject files, 1945-2014; undated; 3
  Series includes files related to research Seelye carried out to support his writings as well as subject files on people and topics of interest to him or related to other work he carried out. Topics vary widely and many files are undated. There are essays, bibliographies, articles, notes, a few illustrations, and some correspondence.
  - A Murder, A Mystery and a Marriage (Mark Twain), 1945 (Box 8)
  - American Endings: Frags, 1986; undated (Box 8)
  - Arkansas, 1945 (Box 8)
  - Avery, G., 1998-2002 (Box 8)
  - "Awsome is as asome does" Am. Maritime Lit.--British Connection Oregon State, 1976 May (Box 8)
  - Black, Robert F., 1965-1974 (Box 8)
  - Book of Mormon as Literature, undated (Box 8)
  - Brodine, Don VA, 1970-1972 (Box 8)
  - Brother Jonathan: Punch Cartoon, 1957 (Box 8)
  - Burgess, Thornton W., 1941 (Box 8)
  - Cannon Fodder MLA, 1990 (Box 8)
  - Captains and captivity narratives, undated (Box 8)
  - Cassius Clay, undated (Box 8)
  - Castaway, 1964; 1975 (Box 8)
  - Cavett file, 1972 (Box 8)
  - Charters, Anne, 1973 (Box 8)
  - Chicago (magazine), 1980-1992 (Box 8)
  - Chicago gothic, undated (Box 8)
  - Collector's prints, 1974 (Box 8)
  - Conroy, Jack, 1969-1972 (Box 8)
  - CPTV (Conn. Public Television) Humor, 1976-1977; undated (Box 8)
  - The Critic, undated (Box 28)
  - Crockett studies, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Cross-stitch (Thinking wild), 1996 (Box 8)
  - Crucifictions, undated (Box 8)
  - Daniel Boone, 1986; 2 folders (Box 31)
  - Davidson--Friend, 1986-1990; undated (Box 8)
  - Dead man's hand, 2013 (Box 8)
  - Elsie the cow, 2011 (Box 8)
  - Emile and the Detective: Salinger, undated (Box 8)
  - Ermme, John--Film proposal, 1986 (Box 8)
  - Fenians invade Canada, 2009 (Box 8)
  - Fool in Hamlet, undated (Box 8)
  - French, Warren, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Friday parody, 1984; undated (Box 8)
  - Gaines, Ernest J., undated (Box 8)
  - Gilgamesh, undated (Box 8)
  - Goldwater, W., 1971 (Box 8)
  - Gray, Herold, 1965; undated (Box 8)
  - Griswold, 1984 (Box 8)
  - The Gulf War, 2005 (Box 8)
  - Hart--Calif. Book Club, 1966-1970 (Box 8)
  - Here we all work on the Mississippi (Coullian), 1956? (Box 8)
  - Here we all work on the Mississippi--M[ark] Twain Reader, undated (Box 8)
  - History as literary art, undated (Box 28)
  - Homer, Winslow, 1995 (Box 8)
  - Hopkins: Spring Rythm, undated (Box 8)
  - Huck Finn (essay), undated (Box 8)
  - Huck Finn: Intro, undated (Box 8)
  - Huck MLA Shenandoah, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Huck Finn Mss, 1991; undated (Box 8)
  - Huck Finn and the Craft of Laughter, undated (Box 8)
  - Huck and Peck's Bad Boy, undated (Box 8)
  - Huckleberry Finn articles, 1970-1985; undated (Box 8)
  - Huckleberry Finn bibliographies, undated (Box 8)
  - Huckleberry Finn, undated (Box 8)
  - Humor, 1950-1960 (Box 28)
  - Imlay novel: notes, undated (Box 8)
  - In Memory of Junior, National Humanities Center "Soundings" (Box 29, Audio-cassette RL11381-CS-005)
    Clyde Edgerton interview at National Humanities Center.
  - Irving, undated (Box 8)
  - Irving and the Passing scenes Vassar, undated (Box 8)
  - Jefferson: father of bastards?, undated (Box 8)
  - John Brown Song, undated (Box 8)
  - Jordan, Peter, 1977 (Box 8)
  - Liebling on Stallman's Letters of Crane, 1961 (Box 8)
  - Lippard, George, 1955-1966 (Box 8)
  - Lubberland revisited, undated (Box 8)
  - M's Moses: Correspondence, etc., 1961; undated (Box 8)
  - M Moses, undated (Box 8)
  - McWilliams, Carey, 1969 (Box 8)
  - Mattias, undated (Box 9)
  - Melville Society, 1968-1969 (Box 9)
  - Melville Society, 1969-1970 (Box 9)
  - Melville Society--General, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Melville Society--Organizational, 1969 (Box 9)
  - Melville Society--Vincent, 1967-1969 (Box 9)
  - Meriwether Lewis, undated (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous notes, undated (Box 9)
  - Miser before Xmas, 2000 (Box 9)
  - Missing Pieces, 1983-1991 (Box 28)
  - MLA--Children's Lit.--West is East corres., 1987 (Box 9)
  - MLA--Human, 1992 (Box 9)
  - M-O American Madness, 1986 (Box 9)
  - Moran, Edward Percy, 2014 (Box 9)
  - The Mouse Book, undated (Box 9)
  - Mr. Dooley Dunne, undated (Box 9)
  - Natchez 92 Lecture, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Neal: Niagara, 2014; undated (Box 9)
  - Notes on Jame's Short Stories, undated (Box 9)
  - On Gaddis, 1962 (Box 9)
  - The Opening (Loch's Play), 1959 (Box 9)
  - Oriand, Michael, 1983 (Box 9)
  - Pagan Perplex, undated (Box 9)
  - Peck, George Wilbur, 1968 (Box 9)
  - Penrod's Barn Defoe Scott, undated (Box 9)
  - Penrod's Barn Kipling, undated (Box 9)
  - Perverse conversions, undated (Box 9)
  - Phelan, AJ, 1969-1972 (Box 9)
  - Phil. Assoc. of Carolinas: Melville and Religion, 1992 (Box 9)
  - Photography (Materials), 1973-1974; undated (Box 9)
  - Pierre and the City, 1991-1992 (Box 9)
  - Pound's Cantos, undated (Box 9)
  - Prologue/ Detocque./ Drafts, undated (Box 9)
  - Puzzle Connection, 1984-2014 (Box 9)
  - Recent work, 2006-2007 (Box 9)
  - Report...on Libraries of the Durham City-Co. Charter Commission by Catherine Maybury, 1960 May (Box 9)
  - Publick Occurences, 1975 (Box 9)
  - Richard Harding Davis (RHD) Materials, undated (Box 9)
  - RHD Notes, undated (Box 9)
  - RHD Search, 1997 (Box 9)
  - Relman corres, 1962-1963 (Box 9)
  - Remington- Wister corres, 1972 (Box 9)
  - Sara Crewe, undated (Box 30)
  - Seelye ancestor, undated (Box 9)
  - Swiss Family Robinson (SFR): Explanatory notes (Final), 1990 (Box 9)
  - Shrews, undated (Box 9)
  - Stallman's Poetry Seminar, 1960 (Box 9)
  - Steinbeck: Language, 1970 (Box 9)
  - Tercentenary celebration (Plymouth), undated (Box 28)
  - Terre Haute, 1994 (Box 9)
  - Throwaway prospectus and intro, undated (Box 9)
  - Tighe, Mike, 1974 (Box 9)
  - Tramp, 1961-1998; 9 folders (Box 28)